Brian Elias Montellano - Software Engineer

(323) 714-8839 | bmontellano@gmail.com | Playa Del Rey, CA

bmontellano.github.io/B E M | github.com/bmontellano | linkedin.com/in/brian-montellano

Summary

I'm a web developer. I currently work with HTML, CSS, and Javascript frameworks (NodeJS, ReactJS), with experience using Ruby on Rails to create full-stack web applications. You can find my work and portfolio on Git + Github. Before developing, I tutored grade school math, science and worked as a laboratory chemist. From these experiences I gained analytical skills, use of complex machinery, troubleshooting by scanning my work for errors, and patience to understand material and deliver it comprehensively. I'm always learning and willing to collaborate and share what I know.

Skills

Computer Languages: Frameworks, Libraries & Technologies:

-HTML5, CSS3, Javascript -Mongo DB, Express, React JS, node.js, Ruby on Rails

-Ruby - jQuery,Bootstrap, SASS, AJAX, JSON

Human Languages: Data modeling - Databases

-Bilingual in Spanish -MongoDB (NoSQL), PostgreSQL (SQL)

Projects

1. HangBoat - web-game using HTML/CSS, Javascript and jQuery for DOM manipulation.

- 2. <u>Cat2Nap</u> full-stack Ruby on Rails application using Amazon Web Services s3. Cat-owners site where individuals can post pictures of their cats, for sitting or showing off purposes.
- 3. <u>RoadRadar</u> full-stack MongoDB, express.js, node.js application. Utilized Agile and SCRUM methodologies for assignment of user stories and tasks to team-members. Crowd sourced reporting of traffic incidents using indicators that have min. ago time stamping, and use of Gmaps API.
- 4. <u>ChatrBoxx</u> full-stack Mongo, Express, Node application. Simple chat application, utilizing Socket.io websockets with RESTful AJAX calls for live chatting and Giphy API to post random GIFs.

Work Experience

Tutor, Study Hut - Oct 2016 to March 2017 Manhattan Beach, CA

- Tutor High School Students in Chemistry, Biology, Physiology, and Mathematics.
- Act as a mentor/coach helping students to create pathways for attainment of higher education

Sales Engineer, American Elements, Merelex Corporation – Jan 2013 to Dec 2014 Los Angeles, CA

- Start-up company environment, manager of sales. Used Filemaker Pro as main database.
- Utilized technical expertise in chemistry to consult clients in selection of advanced compounds.

Research Associate, Molecular Sciences Dept at UCLA- Sept 2011 to May 2012 Los Angeles, CA

- Miguel Garcia-Garibay organic chemistry group synthesizing molecular gyroscopes, stators and rotors.
- Utilized knowledge in organic chemistry and collaborated with associates on synthesis of novel compounds
- Gathered and analyzed data using Nuclear Magnetic Resonance, Mass Spectrometry, and UV spectroscopy.

Research Assistant, Semel Institute for Neuroscience at UCLA – June 2009 to Sept 2009 Los Angeles, CA

- ADHD Research team: Data management using Excel, SAS, and handling human tissue samples.

Tutor, Citrus College - Sept 2006 to May 2008 Glendora, CA

- Tutor of Calculus, Algebra, Trigonometry, and General & Organic Chemistry.
- Received the Tutor of the year award for the 2007-2008 school year.

Education

University of California, Los Angeles - BA in Sociology, Pre-Med with applied chemical research General Assembly, Santa Monica, CA - Web Development Immersive, August 2017